We'll call it over the regular schedule meeting. My I'm City Council, Monday June 5th 2023 Povertary on
a proposed fiscal year 23 24 budget this public hearing is called for any members of
Public to present together by Cometh's recommendations or information
on any part of the proposed by CNN. We'll go into three,
Proclamation declaring June 16th 2023 is Michael Thompson Day in
The City and Milo
And Michael Thomson was a football coach
an eight man football world
He's our president
Of his 8 Man Association Oklahoma had been for several years
And he was part of a big-part
Of date man football game all started getting coming to my Emma and being here for
All these years
He's worked closely with the Mandads say, put this in honor
In our community four year
He passed away
December
So
Of course, eight man game will be coming up here this month and he's been honored there
In more ways than just
His family we would need to recognize so
We decided if you could do that
To give back
This little buddy gave us a mandate
Do whatever
I
For
Proclamation declaring June 1st 2023 is Judy Pittman Day in Miami
So, Judy's worked at Osborne drugs for 40 years
Which it was pretty amazing
For anybody to work
At one place or forty-years that
I know Judy has been awarded several times over the year
The friendless employee of my MITL one time
But she always had a smaller face
She always had a smaller face
So, even though it's already happened
And Brad are here for the proclamation
If we don't vote this is Bradley I want to go get back
But if they kind of brought us to his light notice
When he signed in and sent that way
Hope you guys would
Who?
How about Prolemon
He was on emotion really Brad
Williams
He said
Robert
Bob again but on schedule personal appearances
Six claims
Bruce to approve
Hi
Seven minutes from the May 15th 2023 regga meeting
In a May 22nd 23 special meeting
Second
Hi
Eight, budget amendment
Number 23-24 library
Receiving an adult online
High school grant and donation
Exactly what this amendment does
It allows the library to recede
An expend
And a adult on one highschool Grant
In some donations
About 48 thousand for
A grant
Number 24
Hi
Nine, fiscal year 2324
Municipal budget message
Resolution regarding the city of my amount of money
For his future 23-25 for establishing budget amendment
Authorities and this will be actually number nine
Four in May 2nd
Or city council
So may I remember the Council
And certainly
The citizens at my Emma
Before we get into any necessary discussion
We're voting
I simply wanted to point it out
Two our citizens the amount of effort that goes in
To produce a city's budget
This is something
That, and working on here at this City for several months
Now as you all know
But each department going through
And getting an understanding
Of what their expenses are
What they have to do with revenues
And they're going to be a lot of money
We are not only coming together
To create one unified budget
One for the issue
A and 1 for general fund
So that we may present ultimately
A balanced Budget
Which is what you all know
You have in front
Where we sometimes paint
Staking, and go through
In great detail
Items of the budget
So that
We're going to reach
The council has a mind for our community
As all in
And so with
I want point out few things
To you tonight
Before we open up to that discussion
Just so you have an idea of what
You haven't had any, there's only a few
Probably changes
That has occurred since the last month
However I know i've spoken
Since then
But just point out
One item in
There was The Rainy Day Fund
We discussed making a modification
To
What would be
5.8 million
We reduced that to
4,08
As the ending balance for
The Rainy Day Fund
For next fiscal year
Reduction of
That it could be considered
Not voted on tonight
But only consider in a future
To work out at
The Rainy Day Fund
To represent it to the city
And there's about a million
Dollars on
From
The State
If we can raise additional funds
To complete
A project out There
Regarding our terminal
However its very short notice
We would have to make this
To termination within
This month and then actually be in design by the end of July
So it's a very aggressive schedule
That being said
we need
Find A way that if
If The Council chose
Go after
It will grant her partnership with
With State
We'd like to find it
I can't tell you that it's my recommendation
That we use for today because
We havenít fully vetted yet
Because, still waiting
For our time to work with
Our budget
To not. So
You're marking the main dollar fund
There so if
If
We're going to do that
If you choose not
To Do That
You simply really technically we just don't move the money
But, but
Your basically saying
Put it back into The Rainy Day Fund
No harm no foul
So thats all
We've done.
Are making a decision on how
All of the pros and cons
That being said
There is one highlight in there
Regarding The Airport that we do have a
93.3,000
In
And airport
Budget this year which
Is an airport grant match for
An ongoing five-year project
We'll be doing out at
At A very significant modifications
Which has fantastic
In the budget for streets
Which I know is always a very important
Conversation in The City of Myema
That 2.3 million
Is really made up
Of our funds
Street stadium fund and
Regular street funding that we put
We've been putting it to the budget each year
And then
Then
The city's total combined operating
$154 in revenue
And
85 million
860, 174496
Budget for expenditures
With 9.16% of revenues funded
By eight point nine
Million sales tax and use of shacks
The MSUA revenues fund
Another 42 .25 percent
Of the city of Myema's total revenue budget
So as you can see there
You've got a little over 9% coming from
Sales tax and use of shacks
And 42 percent
Coming
From MSUA
In the rest are other
Revenous
Collectively that make up
That's really presented before
Before
You had to discuss
The first thing you can do
You're talking about a 9.3% growth
9.16%
Now the revenues that's our
8.9 million in sales tax
So,
That is just
A percentage of your own
Revenums
As sales taxes and use tax
To set it here
We spend this fiscal year on street
Of course
Revenums
Okay they spent
2.69
7.61 in the street Malay fund
They have
370, 187
In
1.3 million
Of
The Rben money
If you had a multi-year
And of course that's just the right
So is that number
In the city's labor
Or does it just contractors?
That
Not include labour.
The street department,
It was strictly for repair of roads
And possibly some lease payments
For some equipment
To be over here
The city has a lot
Of course
That comes out of the general fund
that is
The street department in
In a General Fund
So this
This
At
Top there's
A general fund
It has a general fund
But it just on streets
That song
Maintenance
That's all
It is all
So, Tyler
Have an estimate of how many miles
A street you've done in this fiscal year
I think it would be interesting for the public to hear that
We're going
To have a construction subcommittee meeting
Which
You and Brad
Just paid on
And so we got several agenda items
And we find those kind of numbers that you all would like
Then come back and we can present them to the council
But weren't going
We're gonna be well over two million dollars in road construction
Because your at one point nine
You said, That's just a way across
Do what do get ready
To put out the money
Is this appropriate time
Talk about budget allocation too
So
We're going to be able
To put out the money
For our meetings about this funding for
The, um
And we talked
About redoing that
Has
That been done?
So
From CIP to
The MDRA
Essentially for the Coleman
And then, in
In this issue
Which was
Was originally looked at as being done from
That
So that we put it
For a thousand
And then, the thought process behind that is
Anything
That you take from
In this issue
So as a transfer
From MDRA
Ultimately
You're taking revenues
If we aren't careful about how much
We transport mdrs
Ultimately
Because it's going to be calculated to not only recover all of our costs
But in your transfers
We're trying to be really careful with what we transfer
Since they were taking a pretty extensive hit this year
In the issue, it was just costs going up
And everybody knows that inflation has been
So you take
That in multiplied over every project
They've done
Acquisition
Things are running pretty thin
It's an issue
Because
So that's taxed
Generated from people doing online purchases
We had at 400,000 available
That was easy to go
Allocate towards the use of the MDRA money
Ultimately
Thinking
Because we could utilize it for the Coleman
And
The budget
It didn't need a $95,000
A lot
About about
That instead they would do better off with the 400,000
For special projects
So that's what if
The council wants to be re-evaluating
Where money comes from
A couple of different options
We could talk about three different option
With
Of course Mishue is
Normally we were transferred
From 108,000
So if we took it from the 95 thousand
For that would leave a
$13 000
Of course ironically
If you take this
From general fund and left us with
13,000
Projected on their expenditures
That will lead
The MDRA
With 143,00
General fund you could always go ask
In the MDRA for money
Because they would have about 150,000
You really unique position to put
The only other option out there in
Another of those two
Would be reduce expenditure at 400,00
If we look it that
This is quite simply
Really a change
Of course
We would have to pay for the money
To add that 95,000
Back in BRA
So they had a carryover
Because we are all familiar
But it shows its going is 2
The you simply reduce
400,00
And leave them 143,000
Instead of just 43.0
If we left it at the 400,000
They had issues where they were
Needing funding because of whatever
Then what's
The process for using that CIP money
For things other than capital improvement projects
With this resolution you would give
City Manager authority to transfer
Money with inside a fund
So if he wanted
Money from the 400,000
For buildings up to any line
I think that's
The biggest question is we are trying
To promote and have as many events in there
As possible
Because it has a jewel of our town
So i
That big concern
Is doing exactly what you just said running short
Unexpected cost for her show
In your valley
I don't see what's different
This year for last year or the year before
95,000
Just use here
Supply budgets are just really stretched
Because of inflation and things
Costing so much more
So we're trying to reduce
The impact in MESU
We didn t have a negative impact on rights
As you were going
To be looking at rates
We don t want to add that negatively
Anyway, we were trying
To be creative
To fund the coal
Because coven absolutely is
Ground jewelry
And so it doesn't take away
From their ability
The funding of 95,000
Ultimately again
What i'm going
I am try tell you all
You can put money in there
You can't pay for MESU
My recommendation will be
Don t take it from Meshu
Take the general fund or take a FNC
If you taking
To make us to the General Fund then all of them
They ll have more carry over than we will
So that s not even ideal but if possible
We hound our Naked thousand available
Yes, and something
Normally
But this airport transfer
So it's a transfer of 95
Can be a RIA
And next year we ll leave 300.
If you want to take that money out
The CIMC
You can transferred directly so they instead
Of the 44,000 carry over there
A hundred and forty-four thousand dollars are
That s fine
My recommendation would
Very closely with MBRA
They need to come up
And that reserve policy should dictate
What is the intent of those are
Are they building an amount
To repair or
Do additional add-on?
Need be reserved
That s just there
Maybe it's going get a hundred thousand, and thats their buffer
what does expectation
We have other
40s in trust
That we work with
Like MCFA
Also has a fund
And they have reserves
But their reserve is building
To replace turf and explore more
So that would simply be my recommendations
S if you s having an open-ended Reserve
We ll just to plan for it
Why wouldn t I want another 95,000
And we ve got the apartments like a police department
The need more money too
Why wouldn t We do our public piece of officer
To warn that they are part
That needs help
Then, if you trust in depend on
Instead it given us a hold over to
Well I mean thats kind
It was sort
Of those things
There were still so many
We had a quick knowing that
If they got into an issue
Mid year and how to revenue value
They didn t earn the revenue
And I thought it were some of them cancelled
Ultimately, there s going
To come in with city
So we re gonna bail him out
But anyway if you say
About 144.000
True
No employee has ever been laid off
From anything like this
That is not an issue
With hiring people anyway
And we re thinking about giving another department
Another 95,000
A whole family or the homeless
I mean that is a discussion
What your main concern?
If they can be worked out and moved around
My main concerns
Is
The things
That were asking for them to do
Which has been more people
And I appreciate your comments on the fire
In police department
Because everybody needs money
But we get more money by drawing people in and getting sales tax
That s just my biggest concern
If you have a revenue of funding all these other things
Putting our efforts here to do that
but if
We don t,
You can re going
You can re going to pay for the money
But if you don t,
We cant quantify it because its hard
I mean
Can
You cannot get
Without
Those extra sales tax dollars that come in
That s my biggest concern
Other than my
The both theatre
We have one outside deal book which is the
Pliders,
Zyp15
And if we got a carryover of why re booking stuff
If you don t get money there
You should be able to make plans on it
Because I know that i ve seen
That other things are different
You said this was about 30,30
But on your page
There s a list
Causs someone is supposed to know that
That's not from here
So my thesis looks long
We re really excited tonight
If people aren t going
Here are the bottom line
I would want you all
To consider
Ultimately
You heard me talk about the combined total budget
It is 97 million
And we re having quite a extensive conversation
About 95,000
That s all of money but in
The great scheme things
To make or break
If you would not
Make and make it
It wouldn t be fine
At this point
Given what i think
To achieve which is
My understanding
Is you re wanting that carryover
Not before
4,000
If i would recommend
You just pull 95,00
See IP
And simply a change in jail of spreadsheet
How we allocate it
It doesn t changes the image
But what should I want to do
That would allow us to accomplish that
What you are wanting
To do
And then
That will ultimately
You re going
To modify
We ve a jail of has on line
63,000
If she changes it
It changed
In all
The change is
Of the CIP, 400,000
95,00
Just being your mark for operations
Essentially we come carryover
If there are budget holds true
We can be carrying it
Or use that for something else
But 300,000
Is more than adequate
For what?
Like they re going to accomplish in next 12 years
Projects
That Kevin has slated
For this year
Because we still have a lot of things to go
Find out
So, likely the repairs that
We know they re doing
Or you are working at 400,000
See IP funds for our multiple new projects
It wasn t not going
To jump out
Like all
We would be jumping in
Expending 4,00
So what you re working on
What do we want to do?
Given the three options that
We have
From MIMS,
From general fund
I think
The same thing came from the CIP
Without an impact
To get different
For what
We are working on
We talked about the work study
Because we worked in the 95,000
We talk to a part of the 400
If they need it
You want transfer
In fact there is a reserve
Then you would be able
To do same thing as transfer
From MIMS
But at that time
You sign off and then get money
Yeah, if we trade for it they ll have
If more than 144
Then
We re going to talk about
Here
That s kind of the three options
From general fund
But you heard me say that earlier
That would give us less of a reserve
In what
MIMS is not an option
But MIMS could be done
You really don t want to
If you re going on to have to
So the CIP is
Obviously it s funding
It was about once a one time fund
We are talking again
We ll talk in decision this year
This years, right thing
Next we will do
What I would like
To say
The comment
We want to make sure that it is successful
And we will bring in more
That has given
The council of this
In the past and they have
They re years
Transivered up
1660s
We started
There was nothing
There were 25
I think you looked at every year
We used to subsidize the coal
And we re always looking at it
In Kevin will be coming up
The projects that
To update
To fix roof and leaks
Things like this
Which, right now
Or look in a public access
About $1.00
To what reduce in
That was with
The company is going to
Just not that type of
If you re taking something
It s pretty much a museum
And using as an event venue
We wanted it
To truly have and efficient
Self-sustaining
A bit than we would go building
Building
That was designed
To build up
To set the next events
To keep it nice
Keep the safe
I would still like to see
It s getting more out of that building
More events in there
The ginger really nil was a rental
But, its good
Its pretty cool
Good crowd
And we do well
We have a percentage right
That is another significant challenge
And so it s mostly volunteers
If we overbook
Our events
We wear our volunteers out
Then,
There is probably a whole new budget structure
To be looking at
In that maybe something
It counts the ones to talk about
That would say
We should go higher
Conditional staff
And then we would be able to handle more events
We will just have to increase the revenue
I ve another question
Revolving around this
So, i re reading through
The capital improvement
Infrastructure section of
This year a
Capital Improvement Project expenses
From $9804.9949
Repairs of the Coleman Theatre
A sidewalk from my high school
To Elm Street, and resurfacing
So that $400.000 is being allocated to MDRA
Going do all those
That s a way it reads
I did not write
You re talking about this much
And then
Then 400k isn t going
It goes
It reads like it s all inclusive
Okay, that makes me feel better
Guess the only other question is how to do
Department heads fuel about their budgets
Like high tower
Sorry
You put you on a spot
How did he know?
He thought your budget looked over
Kevin
Tyler, good
Right
I chose you last because your the most expensive
You actually have all of them
One thing we do
Is i try to bring out
The directors into budget discussion
Because,
It s possible
We go at it and begin in
First-of year
In different departments
They re going through
They re going through and identify
What their actual expenditures were
And then we go
We start there
Start saying okay, starting at what our
Expendenters where
Where are you?
So from here
We all sit down together
Let s say gasoline
Whatever the actual expenditure
Last year or not
Really terribly relevant
We have a lot of money
And we are going to be very high
You know, vehicle maintenance
Continues
To increase
So go through all that together
Obviously met with council
All-together
So at the end of this week
Last weekend
We all got in the room again
Is there anything we want to discuss
Any questions?
Anything you guys concerned about
To let it be
Before, when used
When do start asking directors
I think that's great
And i am extremely comfortable with this
Then hope
Hope my know how ever would have been answered
So now lorge
You gotta make a background and say
50,000 dollars to the demolition fund
That s for demoing houses
How many houses will that do?
Yeah one
That's best
Sure sure
I mean you are currently on your list
Oh my dear, it is
Something
It should be about right now
We re-today
About what happens
We have a lot of work
About this on the field of burn
So I see it all
That was an old property in the 6th moment
Who is up at 2 store
Do we want to do that
To $200,000
Housing
And then
We were talking about
But thats also an option
The main use for demoing
Go and forward
That was kind of the trade-off
We are going to get what they wanted to do
So that it would give us stability
You want
Can't we can now
I mean its like
Now, contract
It will allow
Uses
That money for
Reemation of substated houses
That can happen
Some of that money for demoing
As long as they approve it
Thats one
One is the modification
We are really trading in fours
Get rid
If we wanted to use
From this purpose now
You feel like
I think you have a greater data
They believe
You have a bigger data
But you are going to do that
And then
That will be wonderful
Ok
We want to make sure we say
The only reason I ask is
Because i know most departments
Issue, every officer
So thats why
If they work in one
Then the law gives someone
To our
Underhand
Or to the rest
I just want
Appreciate everybody's efforts in this
It is a lot of work
The citizens money
So, you know
They are scrutinized for reasons
But
We understand that the amount
That was put into it
That our performer information tells us over the last few years
We have done budgets that we are doing something right
So, in lieu of
I would make a motion
Yes
If
What is approved
The resolution will be redrafted
In order to bring it
And place but thats not keeping
Whatever you are going to decide tonight
We can just have
Because thats the easier approach
Transferring your motion
That was what i didn't want
Using any other funding
With a amendment that would ultimately result
From
The transfer from CIP
And carry over
143,000
So, the 138,000
944 and 97
Yes
That was on
For both
The city boat
The M.C., M.A
The M.S..
I think there is no amendment to it
No, theres a motion
Back
We have to close the door
Make most of it during M.A
So, move
A step
To pull
And ten
Stangly work with civic plus LLC
Municipal co-operation
For code of ordinance
Okay so
Every time we do an ordinance
It has to be updated in our
Cronordman's books and online
And this is the company that we would like
To utilize
To print those supplements
Make sure they are online
But i never know how it will get before
No, its not same company
Technically civic plus bought municode
So
Its an amendment
Contract with civic plus
That same price is last year
Is that 5% increase as you
What they are doing
There's an option to pay per ordinance
Or what we have opted
To do if approved by council
We would want
Pay a set fee
And then can write many ordinances
As he can, and
Can all be in making cheaper
And she did the math, I saw
The only problem with that is we also have to publish it in
Newspaper and thats where i could cost you
But regardless
We had To do both
Take it
Hi
11 or table
Because they paid the certain value
And we had to pay a lot of money
This was an ordinance that passed
A year ago, basically
That Had
An incorrect legal description
I would point out it
Was The Other Law from
Wrote that Ornance
We are correcting the legal descriptions
So It Weekend
Actually move forward with what we are trying to do here
They simply left off
And the legal description that it was
Plat 3
The Weekend
This is
No, this Is
A TNT had no problems
With
This Ornance
I mean It's up
I mean It's up to you, certainly
Can if You feel it is potentially a problem
But i felt like we did the one that
We were at The Seen Your Sees
Yeah
They think he was
Just carrying my money
Well there Is nothing wrong with doing this
We still get it to college
So for the emergency laws we will need
For
Call like you
I don't think i would go
Second
Is there
Hi
14 is The Words
Say
Okay
Hi
Let's talk about Grant
23 series
Authorised the City Manor Sign
We have Caitlin here
Okay so The grant is
From the Equalment Humanities
It $1,500
And we cost share it with
With a total of 3,799.49 cents
So its
In between 45 books
And we have a total of 2,799.
So the theme is
The Cowboy
I'm reading some historical cowboys
Including Reminance from real
Cowboys and fictional depictions
From Owen Wisters
It's A Great Way for Dull to Come in
Listen To Forza
Some ones specifically on their list
That week
But it was a good time
It's nice to see the community come out
I don't think its big is
The last one they did back in February
For January
So we had an hour and day
And that wasn t crazy
A lot of fun this when
We even didn s specialised Grandracing
If you never done
I was going to see the community out
And i like that we re doing more of these outdoor events
Just trying people creating buzz
Its awesome
Up here you back on a little bit
Your council in the Bryan did race
That Grandracing
But he didn't get beat by guy with milk
Crane in the back of his butt
Really?
No brining at F1
Yeah its blessed
You know whenever that Grandracing came up
I had a lot of discussion Kevin
And guys, they talked about whether
They could do the grandracing out there everything
But it happened its fun
Nobody crashed
We re letting people have fun
Because if we don t let them be on here
Then you go to find some more else
At least i did this
And these Grandracing never heard of it
Had no idea what they were
But i looked like their fun
It s old to blast
I guess that ride trails around here too
There is a bunch
A trail down by the river
Im just glad we re able
To look into and make sure
We could offer safely
Insurance was available
And they were not allowed to make sure
They re making a way for whatever
I think the right way
We got Brian signed up
i wouldn t call him his wife and he had heard
He was at back of pack
That wasn't one other guy
Oh, isn s trying
To be your Grandracing, just wanted an headphone
So a 19
I have several things to mention
There s lot going on right now
The my little theater presents the
Succuled Junior this week
That is cast of all children from grades 3-12
And it shows musical with Dr. Sue's themes
It was so soon
Two times or Thursday and Friday 7pm
In Saturday at 2 p
Also, MSRP started today
Currently we have 145 kids on road
Fantastic
Pull it up into Marrow for 1-6
Of course, we re still accepting applications
For all positions
Splashpad is open 7 days a week from 8 to eight
Splashpad has been crazy busy every time I drive by there
It s packed and that was really cool
Pignic tables, cornhole boards
We are at last weekend which
We are at a high level
And we have a lot of people
I can t wait to go and try it
To get out there
Monsters trucks will be in the fairgrounds this week
6-9 through 16
Pitcher all school reunion
We ll visit the Civic Center on the temple
In sports and wreck
Having great success with youth, softball
Expect more good things
It s an amazing job so we are thrilled to have him
Focusing on this season
Animal control has fixed 80 plus cats
Trapped new release program
Problemers were being addressed in citation
All good stuff
Appreciate all the hard work, Councils done
To help us get into his point
Most
We will visit the Civic Center
Now we ll go to order
MIFA for my age in 5th, 2023